Guide to the Jimenez Family Papers TAM.838
Tamiment Library and Robert F. Wagner Labor Archives
- Jimenez, Michael A. -- UA, IAM, and Other Employment and Activism, 1941-1959 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Letter Jean T. McKelvey NYS Board of Mediation to MAJ -- Thank You, 1956-01-11
  - Copy of Letter E. R. White to UE District No. 3 re: Proposal UE District 3 Local Affiliation with IAM, 1956-05-21
  - Letter Elmer E. Walker IAM to MAJ re: Appointment as Special Representative Effective 1956-05-16, 1956-06-05
  - Letter Richard Arens, Director, House Committee on Un-American Activities to Congressman Dean P. Taylor, 1956-06-13
  - Memo to Congressman Taylor from House Committee on Un-American Activities on MAJ, 1956-06-13
  - Copy of Letter Larry Cover IAM Indiana to E. R. White IAM re: MAJ Assistance with Negotiations with Square D Company, 1956-09-17
  - Letter NYS School of Industrial and Labor Relations Cornell University to MAJ re: Request to Speak to Classes for Jean T. McKelvey and Alice H. Cook in January 1957, 1956-10-30
  - Letter Eric Peterson IAM to MAJ re: Completion of Investigation into Eligibility for Membership and Decision (No Charges Filed), 1956-12-12
  - Letter Alice H. Cook NYS School of Industrial and Labor Relations Cornell University to MAJ re: Content for Labor Union History Class, 1956-12-13
  - Letter Eric Peterson IAM to MAJ re: Salary Increase, 1957-01-04
  - Copy of Letter Jean McKelvey NYS Board of Mediation to Ernest White IAM re: Appearance by MAJ and Wayne Horvitz in Cornell Class on Collective Bargaining, 1957-01-11
  - Copy of Letter MAJ IAM to E. R. White IAM Resigning Sosition as Special Representative Completing Assignments by 1957-04-30, 1957-04-23
  - MAJ IAM Application for Honorary Withdrawal Card Approved 1957-05-22, 1957-04-23
  - Copy of Letter E. R. White IAM to A. J. Hayes IAM re: MAJ Resignation Proposing with Vacation Effective Date 1957-05-14, 1957-04-26
  - Letter Elmer E. Walker IAM to MAJ re: Effective Date of Resignation and Vacation, 1957-04-30
  - Receipts from the Appearance of before the Senate Internal Security Subcommittee, 1957-05-05-1957-05-18
  - Letter Joseph Vinci IAM to MAJ Transmitting Honorary Withdrawal Card after Unanimous Vote by Membership, 1957-05-23
  - Orders to Appear before the Senate Internal Security Subcommittee, 1957-05-29
  - Telegram Text from A. J. Hayes IAM to John Murray IAM Requesting Information on Issuance of MAJ Honorary Withdrawal Card, 1957-06-07
  - Copy of Letter John Murray IAM to A. J. Hayes Providing Information on MAJ Withdrawal and Issuance of Honorary Withdrawal Card, 1957-06-10
  - Copy of Letter MAJ to Joseph Vinci IAM Returning Honorary Withdrawal Card, 1957-08-05
  - Letter Jacob Maracchion IAM to MAJ Acknowledging Receipt of Honorary Withdrawal Card, 1957-08-09
  - Pamphlet Grand Lodge International Association of Machinists Minutes of the Executive Council including "Reports on the Investigating Committee on Cases of Michael Jimenez Joseph Infante, Charles Steiner, and Sterling O. Neal, and the Placing of Charges", 1957-09-04-1957-09-12
  - Letter M. R. Stern IAM to MAJ re: Charges by Members Eric Peterson and George Christensen for Violation of Section 3, Article K of IAM Constitution and Planned Investigation, Hearing and Report, 1957-09-30
  - Copy Statement of Charges by Eric Peterson and George Christensen re: MAJ Alleged Violations of IAM Constitution for Communist Activities, 1957-09-27
  - Copy of Letter A. J. Hayes IAM to Elmer E. Walker, Fred H. Cooley and Eric Melton IAM re: Appointment of Three as Members of Special Committee to Investigate MAJ, 1957-09-30
  - IAM Fact Finding Investigations Official Circular No. 490, 1948-01-20
  - Copy of Letter MAJ to A. J. Hayes as Reply to 1957-09-30 Letter M. R. Stern IAM to MAJ, Noting MAJ Cancellation of Honorary Withdrawal Card and Statement against Investigation, 1958-01-15
  - Letter A. J. Hayes IAM to MAJ Requesting Proof of Cancellation of Honorary Withdrawal, 1958-01-20
  - Copy of Letter Elmer E. Walker IAM to Eric Peterson, George W. Christensen, Joseph Infante, MAJ and Charles Steiner re: Consolidation of Investigations, 1958-01-20
  - Copy of Letter MAJ to A. J. Hayes IAM re: Proof of Cancellation of Honorary Withdrawal, 1958-01-27
  - Copy of Letter George Christensen to Elmer E. Walker, Fred H. Cooley and Earl Melton IAM re: Illness of Plaintiff Witness Loyd Kinsey, 1958-02-05
  - Copy of Letter Elmer E. Walker IAM to George W. Christensen IAM re: Deposition from Loyd Kinsey, 1958-02-07
  - Copy of Letter A. J. Hayes IAM to Elmer E. Walker IAM re: Evidence for MAJ Case, 1958-02-10
  - Copy of Letter A. J. Hayes to Eric Peterson, George W. Christensen and MAJ re: End of MAJ Charges Due to Lack of Status that would Allow Charges, 1958-04-02
- Jimenez, Michael A. -- UA, IAM Photographs, 1941-1959 (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Jimenez, Michael A. -- Newspaper Articles (UE, IAM, and Other Subjects), 1940-1959 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - MAJ in "UE Fighters Win Medals for Valor," in Front Page Tearsheet from UE News, Issue No. 1, 131, circa 1945
  - MAJ in "Army Decorates UE Men for Outstanding Service" in Newspaper Clipping from UE News, 1945-07-18
  - MAJ in "Guerrilla Specialist Warns Us 'Must Learn to Live With All" in The CIO NEWS, p.2, 1945-07-30
  - MAJ in "Specialist in Guerrilla Warfare" in UE News, 1945-07-21
  - "Guerrilla Warfare Specialist" in The Worker, p. 5, 1945-08-05
  - MAJ in "Much-Decorated Camp McQuaide Captain Has Ambitious Post-War Plans" in Over and Shorts, California, Vol 3, No. 49, p. 1, 1945-09-08
  - Copy of Newspaper Clipping -- "They Have Served With Honor", circa 1945
  - "Jimenez Is Attached In Rand Statement: Strike Charges Exchanged" in Utica Observer-Dispatch, 1947-06-27
  - "Behind Pay Rolls In Triple Cities: UE Sends Another Politician-Laborite Into This Area", 1951-04-05
  - "Labor Party will Run Jimenez for Congress" in Rome Daily Sentinel, 1952-07-12
  - "Rome Union Leader Hits Fuller Record in House", circa 1950
  - "Jimenez Hurls 'Cheap Hoax' Charge at Proposed Hearing: Calls McCarthy 'Master Faker'" in Utica Daily Press, 1953-12-04
  - "Jimenez Denies Present Communist Affiliation", 1956
  - "City Man Denies Being Member of Red Party", 1956
  - "Jimenez Enters Labor Relations" in Buffalo Evening News, 1957-05-23
  - "Art Metal Co., Crescent Tool Are Negotiating", circa 1957
  - "Jimenez Denies He's Communist But Refuses to Say If He Ever Was: Organizers Use Amendment 5 in Washington," Utica Observer-Dispatch, Section 2, p. 1-A, 1957-06-07
  - "Former O.S.S Aide Balks on Red Links" in New York Times, 1957-06-07
  - "And Who Gave Jiminez His Captaincy in Army?", 1957-06-18
  - "How Did a Pro-Red Become a U.S. Spy?" in N.Y. Daily Mirror, 1957-06-18
  - "Overtime Parking Case To Be Tried on June 6" in Rome Daily Sentinel, circa 1940s-1950s
- Jimenez, Michael A. -- Senate Sub-Committee and FBI, 1957-1958 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Copy of Letter Richard Arens House Un-American Activities Committee to Dean P. Taylor re: Reports on Julius Emspak, Albert Fitzgerald, James Matles, MAJ and Tom Flanagan, 1956-06-13
  - Copy of Information from the US House of Representatives Files of the Committee on Un-American Activities to Dean P. Taylor re: MAJ, 1956-06-13
  - James C. Eastland Order to Appear Internal Subcommittee of the Senate Judiciary to MAJ for 1957-06-06, 1957-05-29
  - Receipt from Attorney David Scribner for MAJ Representation at Senate Internal Security Subcommittee, 1957-06-05
  - Receipt from US Senate for Attendance at Senate Internal Security Subcommittee, 1957-06-18
  - MAJ Statement on Attempted FBI Recruitment by Robert Margison, 1958-05-11
- Pension Claim (IAM) by Fried, Jimenez, Landy, Infante, 1970s-1980s (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Card from Law Office of Collins, Collins, DiNardo, Buffalo NY with Handwritten Name of Susan Silber, undated
  - Letter Emanuel Fried to MAJ on Labor Arts Books Stationery re: Possibilities for IAM Pension Claim Based on 15 years Service in UE, 1975-10-08
  - Letter Edward Landy to MAJ re: IAM Pension Claim, Possible Advice from William Winpisinger, President International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers, circa 1977
  - Letter Emanuel Fried to MAJ re: Possibilities for IAM Pension Claim and Costs, 1977-10-04
  - Copy of Letter Bruce Willson District Lodge 76 IAM to Lew King, Ed Landy, Thomas Flanagan, Joseph Infante, Emanuel Fried, Sheridan Creekmore re: Initiation Process from UE to IAM Membership and Employment, 1956-06-04
  - Copy of Letter Elmer E. Walker IAM to Emanuel Fried re: Appointment as Special Representative Effective 1956-05-16, 1956-06-05
  - Copy of Letter Eric Peterson IAM to Eric Peterson re: IAM Membership, 1956-06-05
  - Copy of Letter Emanuel Fried to Eric Peterson IAM re: Terms of UE-IAM Affiliation, 1956-06-07
  - Copy of Employment Application by Emanuel J. Fried to IAM, 1956-06-07
  - Copy of Open Letter Eugene Tooke, George H. Olmstead, Frank Lacey, Robert Stenzel, Herbert M. Melius, John Pastor, Carl Lee Payne to Executive Council, IAM re: Dismissal of Emanuel J. Fried, Edward Landy and Thomas Flanagan, circa 1956
  - Copy of Letter Eric Peterson IAM to Emanuel J. Fried re: Membership, 1956-06-25
  - Copy of Letter Emanuel Fried to William Winpisinger IAM re: Pension Claim, 1977-08-23
  - Copy of Letter Emanuel Fried to William Winpisinger IAM re: Additional Info on Pension Claim, 1977-08-24
  - Copy of Letter William Winpisinger IAM to Emanuel Fried re: his Investigation of IAM Records about Pension Claim, 1977-09-19
  - Letter Emanuel Fried to MAJ re: Affidavit in IAM Pension Claim, 1978-01-09
  - Copy of Memo MAJ to Emanuel Fried Promising Affidavit, 1977-11-06
  - Copy of Letter from Attorney Susan Silber to William Winpisinger IAM re: Pension Claim, 1978-06-14
  - Copy of Letter from Attorney Susan Silber to MAJ, Edward Landy, Emanuel Fried, Joseph Infante re: IAM Pension Claim and Lack of Response by Winpisinger, 1978-06-14
  - Copy of Letter from Attorney John F. Collins to MAJ, Edward Landy, Emanuel Fried, Joseph Infante re: IAM Pension Claim after Review of Work of Susan Silber, 1978-08-29
  - Memo Emanuel Fried to MAJ re: Advice by John F. Collins, circa 1978
  - Copy of Note Beatrice (Beady) Infante to Emanuel Fried on Copy of Newspaper Article re: Death of Joseph C. Infante, circa 1978
  - Memo Emanuel Fried to MAJ re: Note from Beatrice Infante, circa 1978
  - Copy of Memo MAJ to Emanual Fried Transmitting Newspaper Court Action, 1979-06-16
  - Letter Emanuel Fried to MAJ re: Strategy for Pension Claim and "Drop Hammer" Play in LA with Help of Roy Jimenez, 1979-06-22
  - Newspaper Clipping -- "High Court to Decide if Seniority System Has Exemption from Civil Rights Act", circa 1979
  - Copy of Memo MAJ to Attorney Martin R. Bradley re: Meeting in Buffalo, 1979-09-07
  - Letter from Attorney Martin R. Bradley to MAJ re: Meeting in Buffalo, circa September 1979
  - Newspaper Clipping -- Buffalo Courier Express, "Critics Acclaim Works of Buffalo's Neglected Playwright" Regarding Production of "Drop Hammer" in Los Angeles, 1980-02-10
  - Newspaper Clipping -- Boston Globe, "Unionist Wimpy Winpisinger: He's Battling for Men's Minds", 1981-09-28
  - Letter Robert B. Druar to Emanuel Fried, Edward Landy, Michael Jimenez and Beatrice Infante re: Feasibility of Lawsuit against IAM for Pension Claim, 1983-02-14
  - "Appeal of Emanuel Fried" re: Appeal to IAM District 76 to Pass Resolution and Lead Support of Pension Claim, 1983-03-14
  - Letter Emanuel Fried to MAJ and Edward Landy re: Appeal to IAM Local District 76 with Help from John Wilson, President of IAM 2115 and District 76, 1983-03-18
  - Copy of Letter To Whom It May Concern from Eugene C. Tooke re: 1956 Negotiations between UE District 3 Local and IAM and the mMovement of Locals to IAM, 1983-04-02
  - Letter Emanuel Fried to MAJ re: 1983-04-02 Tooke Letter, 1983-04-07
  - Envelope to from Emanuel Fried to Edward Landy, 1983-03-19
  - Copy of Newspaper Clipping -- The Buffalo News, "Playwright Files Pension Suit", 1983-07-19
  - Copy of Letter Robert B. Druar to Emanuel Fried re: Commencement of Lawsuit in US District Court Western District of NY, 1983-07-20
  - Copy of Memo MAJ to Emanual Fried re: Pension Claim, 1983-07-28
  - Letter from Robert B. Druar to Emanuel Fried, Edward Landy, and Michael Jimenez about Commencement of Federal Lawsuit, 1983-08-04
  - Complaint in the Matter of "Emanuel Fried, Edward Landy and Michael Jimenez against The Pension Plan of the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers" in US District Court for Western NY, 1983
  - Robert B. Druar Memorandum of Law "Emanuel Fried, Edward Landy and Michael Jimenez against The Pension Plan of the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers and the International Association of Machinists and Aerospace Workers" in US District Court for Western NY, 1983-11-18
  - Memo Emanuel Fried to MAJ re: Waiting for Judge Curtin's Ruling on Pension Case, 1983-12-04
  - Letter MAJ to Robert B. Druar re: Background on UE/IAM Membership and Recommended Discovery for Lawsuit, 1983-12-27
  - Newspaper Page -- The Buffalo News including "Labor Comment" Column by Joe Ritz titled "Three Pensions At Heart of Lawsuit", 1984-02-11
  - IAM Constitution, pages 34-41, circa 1950s
  - Handwritten Notes by MAJ, undated
  - Copy of Loyalty Oath (Unsigned) by MAJ, 1959-01-05
- OSS Allotment Effort (Lossowski, Vince), circa 1980s (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Letter from Vince Lossowski to MAJ Regarding Effort to Get Supplementary Allotments for Dependents from OSS, 1983-07-28
  - Copy of Letter from Congressman Frank Horton to U.S. Army Colonel Hershell Murray Requesting Assistance in Resolving the Issue, 1982-06-14
  - Memo from Horton to Lossowski Offering to Introduce a Special Bill, 1982-07-30
  - Copy of Letter from US Army J.R. Bain to Horton Suggesting a Special Bill, 1982-07-20
  - Copy of Letter from Lossowski to Horton Saying Yes to Special Bill, 1982-08-10
  - Copy of Letter from Horton to Lossowski Suggesting a Special Bill, 1982-08-16
  - Copy of Letter from Lossowski to Horton on Failure of Special Bill and Offer to Try Again, 1983-07-22
  - Letter from Lossowski to MAJ Asking for Corroboration of OSS Promise, 1983-10-23
  - Copy of Affidavit from MAJ Regarding OSS Promise, circa 1983
- Jimenez, Michael A. -- Insurance, Real Estate Employment, 1958-1960 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Letter from Milton I. Weiss, Columbian National Life Insurance Company to MAJ re: Delay in Decision on Application for License Due to Review by NYS Insurance Department of Union Members, 1958-11-25
  - Letter from Walter Brooks, NYS Insurance Department to MAJ Confirming Need for Oath, 1958-12-23
  - Copy of Letter from MAJ to Walter Brooks, NYS Insurance Department responding to 1958-12-23 Request for Oath, 1959-01-05
  - Letter from Douglas S. Felt, Empire State Mutual Life Insurance Company to MAJ Regarding his and Joe Infante's Agent's Licenses and Broker's Contracts, 1959-01-26
  - MAJ NYS License Card as Real Estate Salesman for Broker Stanley Rebisz, 722 W. Dominick Street, Rome, NY, 1960-09-28
- Jimenez, Michael A. -- Car Wash Employment, 1960-1961 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Business Cards for MAJ as Mini-Wash and Aqua-Mizer, undated
  - Copy of Letter from MAJ to Alfred Johnson, Marine Midland Trust Company for a Construction Loan for Mini-Wash, 1969-10-14
  - The Sherman SuperSonic News, March/April 1964
  - Promotional/Business Materials about Mini-Wash and Aqua-Mizer, a Water Filtration and Reclamation System, 1991-09-23
- Jimenez, Michael A. -- Obituary, 1991 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Jimenez, Mary Rachel (Walton) -- Documents and Newspaper Articles, circa 1950s-2007 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Clipping from Rome Daily Sentinel of MWJ Letter to Editor "Cites Urey Letter on Rosenberg Case to Prove Trial Unconvincing", circa 1950s
  - MWJ Obituary (Published in Rome Daily Sentinel), 2007